## **CAO YU**

@ ricardo\_cao@foxmail.com

Beijing, CHINA

**%** +8613691214473

**6** 08/08/1994



#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Baidu

#### **Front-End Engineer**

## 2019 - Ongoing

<u>baidu.com</u> is top1 chinese search engine and top3 internet company in China.

- buildiing big data visualize platform with VueJs / EchartsJs
- Auto mail building and sending service with ExpressJs and NodemailJs
- · Big Data Visualize Platform H5 version with VueJs
- building monitor system, including bug monitor and performance monitor
- Use Scrapy/Python make spider to crawl info like news and reports

## Xiaozhu

#### **Front-End Engineer**

**2018 - 2019** 

xiaozhu.com is top2 accomadation sharing company in China which the other one is Airbnb.

- Rebuild <u>m.xiaozhu.com</u> H5 website front-end part with VueJS
- Building activity page auto-building platform with VueJS and ExpressJS, supporting drag components into indicated area and viewing result at the same time, using NodeJS/HandlebarJS auto create vitual dom and start a webserver for each developing project, managing process to control internal memory.
- Optim]ize front-end performance from 2.1s to 1.03s for first page view

## ZTE

#### **Front-End Engineer**

**2016 - 2018** 

zte is one of wolrd-wide top 4 communication equipment companys which the other three are Huawei/Nokia/Erricson.

- Handle with ZTE smartphone mall with JQueryJS
- Making activity pages to support daily marketing activity.

### **EDUCATION**

# Electronic Engineering Chongging University(CHINA)

Ranking: Top 20 In China

**#** 2012 - 2016

## **PROFILE**

I'm a three years experience Front-End Engineer, looking for a Front-End engineer job oversea.

I've got experience with millions-user's website frontend constructing and complex logic coding, good at handle with bugs and optimize web performance.

## **SKILLS**

- JavaScript (ES6 / ES7)
- VueJS
- ReactJS
- Redux / VueX
- HTML5 / CSS3
- NodeJS
- MySQL

## **GITHUB**

https://github.com/rico-c